[
    {
        "question": "وَأَبًّا",
        "answer": "and grass",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 4,
        "tlit": "wa-abban",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَاكِهَةً وَأَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "أ ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ب ب",
        "waznEnglish": "grass, herbage, pasture",
        "waznTlit": "hamza bā bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَبِيهِ",
        "answer": "and his father",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "wa-abīhi",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأُمِّهِ وَأَبِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبٌ",
        "waznEnglish": "father",
        "waznTlit": "abun",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَخِيهِ",
        "answer": "his brother",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 23,
        "tlit": "akhīhi",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَفِرُّ الْمَرْءُ مِنْ أَخِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخ",
        "waznEnglish": "brother",
        "waznTlit": "akh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "357",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِذَا شَاءَ أَنْشَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "But when",
        "pcklId": "358",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الصَّاخَّةُ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "452",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍa",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ شَقَقْنَا الْأَرْضَ شَقًّا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "at",
        "pcklId": "730",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلْيَنْظُرِ الْإِنْسَانُ إِلَىٰ طَعَامِهِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمَرَهُ",
        "answer": "He commanded him",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amarahu",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَمَّا يَقْضِ مَا أَمَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to order, to command",
        "waznTlit": "amara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأُمِّهِ",
        "answer": "And his mother",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 72,
        "tlit": "wa-ummihi",
        "frequency": "119",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأُمِّهِ وَأَبِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُمّ",
        "waznEnglish": "mother, foundation, final abode",
        "waznTlit": "umm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمَّا",
        "answer": "As for",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمَّا مَنِ اسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "But as for",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ جَاءَكَ يَسْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "[the] man",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قُتِلَ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا أَكْفَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "the man",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلْيَنْظُرِ الْإِنْسَانُ إِلَىٰ طَعَامِهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَرَرَةٍ",
        "answer": "dutiful",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 114,
        "tlit": "bararatin",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كِرَامٍ بَرَرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "you do good",
        "waznTlit": "barr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَبْشِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "rejoicing at good news",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "mus'tabshiratun",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ضَاحِكَةٌ مُسْتَبْشِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَبْشِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "mus'tabshirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَنِيهِ",
        "answer": "and his children",
        "pcklId": "175",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "wabanīhi",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَصَاحِبَتِهِ وَبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَهُ",
        "answer": "came to him",
        "pcklId": "271",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāahu",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ جَاءَهُ الْأَعْمَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَكَ",
        "answer": "came to you",
        "pcklId": "272",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāaka",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ جَاءَكَ يَسْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَتِ",
        "answer": "comes",
        "pcklId": "273",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāati",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الصَّاخَّةُ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَبًّا",
        "answer": "grain",
        "pcklId": "88",
        "rootWordId": 284,
        "tlit": "ḥabban",
        "frequency": "95",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا حَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "ح ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "has endeared",
        "waznTlit": "ḥabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحَدَائِقَ",
        "answer": "And gardens",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 299,
        "tlit": "waḥadāiqa",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَدَائِقَ غُلْبًا",
        "rootWord": "ح د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح د ق",
        "waznEnglish": "gardens",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā dāl qāf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْشَىٰ",
        "answer": "fears",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 410,
        "tlit": "yakhshā",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَهُوَ يَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَشِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear",
        "waznTlit": "khashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَهُ",
        "answer": "He created him",
        "pcklId": "170",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqahu",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ أَيِّ شَيْءٍ خَلَقَهُ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَهُ",
        "answer": "He created him",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqahu",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ نُطْفَةٍ خَلَقَهُ فَقَدَّرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُدْرِيكَ",
        "answer": "would make you know",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "yud'rīka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يُدْرِيكَ لَعَلَّهُ يَزَّكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذَكَرَهُ",
        "answer": "may remember it",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhakarahu",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنْ شَاءَ ذَكَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remember, to mention",
        "waznTlit": "dhakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَذَّكَّرُ",
        "answer": "be reminded",
        "pcklId": "150",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "yadhakkaru",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوْ يَذَّكَّرُ فَتَنْفَعَهُ الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to receive admonition",
        "waznTlit": "tadhakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the reminder",
        "pcklId": "193",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'rā",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوْ يَذَّكَّرُ فَتَنْفَعَهُ الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَذْكِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a reminder",
        "pcklId": "284",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "tadhkiratun",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّهَا تَذْكِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذْكِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "tadhkirat",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَرْفُوعَةٍ",
        "answer": "Exalted",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 573,
        "tlit": "marfūʿatin",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " مَرْفُوعَةٍ مُطَهَّرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّرْفُوعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and We raised",
        "waznTlit": "marfūʿat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْهَقُهَا",
        "answer": "Will cover them",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 596,
        "tlit": "tarhaquhā",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْهَقُهَا قَتَرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ه ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْهَقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "yarhaqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَزَّكَّىٰ",
        "answer": "purify himself",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 624,
        "tlit": "yazzakkā",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يُدْرِيكَ لَعَلَّهُ يَزَّكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ك و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "tazakkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَزَّكَّىٰ",
        "answer": "he purifies himself",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 624,
        "tlit": "yazzakkā",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا عَلَيْكَ أَلَّا يَزَّكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ك و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "tazakkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَزَيْتُونًا",
        "answer": "And olive",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 642,
        "tlit": "wazaytūnan",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَزَيْتُونًا وَنَخْلًا",
        "rootWord": "ز ي ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَّيْتُون",
        "waznEnglish": "its oil",
        "waznTlit": "zaytūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّبِيلَ",
        "answer": "the way",
        "pcklId": "175",
        "rootWordId": 656,
        "tlit": "l-sabīla",
        "frequency": "176",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ السَّبِيلَ يَسَّرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ب ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the way",
        "waznTlit": "sīn bā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْعَىٰ",
        "answer": "striving",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "yasʿā",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ جَاءَكَ يَسْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to strive, to run",
        "waznTlit": "saʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَفَرَةٍ",
        "answer": "(of) scribes",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 695,
        "tlit": "safaratin",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَيْدِي سَفَرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَفَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "it brightens",
        "waznTlit": "safarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْفِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) bright",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 695,
        "tlit": "mus'firatun",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ مُسْفِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْفِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "it brightens",
        "waznTlit": "mus'firat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَأْنٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a matter",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 753,
        "tlit": "shanun",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لِكُلِّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ شَأْنٌ يُغْنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ش أ ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش أ ن",
        "waznEnglish": "any situation",
        "waznTlit": "shīn hamza nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَقَقْنَا",
        "answer": "We cleaved",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 787,
        "tlit": "shaqaqnā",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ شَقَقْنَا الْأَرْضَ شَقًّا",
        "rootWord": "ش ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَقَقْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make difficult, to cleave",
        "waznTlit": "shaqaq",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَقًّا",
        "answer": "splitting",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 787,
        "tlit": "shaqqan",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ شَقَقْنَا الْأَرْضَ شَقًّا",
        "rootWord": "ش ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "make it difficult",
        "waznTlit": "shaqq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "wills",
        "pcklId": "229",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنْ شَاءَ ذَكَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "He wills",
        "pcklId": "230",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِذَا شَاءَ أَنْشَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "thing",
        "pcklId": "516",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ أَيِّ شَيْءٍ خَلَقَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَبَبْنَا",
        "answer": "[We] poured",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 816,
        "tlit": "ṣababnā",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّا صَبَبْنَا الْمَاءَ صَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pour",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَبًّا",
        "answer": "(in) abundance",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 816,
        "tlit": "ṣabban",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّا صَبَبْنَا الْمَاءَ صَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "Will be poured",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabb",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَصَاحِبَتِهِ",
        "answer": "And his wife",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "waṣāḥibatihi",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَصَاحِبَتِهِ وَبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَٰحِبَة",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāḥibat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُحُفٍ",
        "answer": "sheets",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 823,
        "tlit": "ṣuḥufin",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي صُحُفٍ مُكَرَّمَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُحُف",
        "waznEnglish": "plates",
        "waznTlit": "ṣuḥuf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّاخَّةُ",
        "answer": "the Deafening Blast",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 824,
        "tlit": "l-ṣākhatu",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا جَاءَتِ الصَّاخَّةُ",
        "rootWord": "ص خ خ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص خ خ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Deafening Blast",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād khā khā",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَصَدَّىٰ",
        "answer": "give attention",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 831,
        "tlit": "taṣaddā",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْتَ لَهُ تَصَدَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَصَدَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give attention",
        "waznTlit": "taṣaddā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَاحِكَةٌ",
        "answer": "Laughing",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 881,
        "tlit": "ḍāḥikatun",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " ضَاحِكَةٌ مُسْتَبْشِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ض ح ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَاحِكَة",
        "waznEnglish": "So let them laugh",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāḥikat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَعَامِهِ",
        "answer": "his food",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 911,
        "tlit": "ṭaʿāmihi",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلْيَنْظُرِ الْإِنْسَانُ إِلَىٰ طَعَامِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ط ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَعَام",
        "waznEnglish": "taste it",
        "waznTlit": "ṭaʿām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُطَهَّرَةٍ",
        "answer": "purified",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 928,
        "tlit": "muṭahharatin",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مَرْفُوعَةٍ مُطَهَّرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّطَهَّرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they are cleansed",
        "waznTlit": "muṭahharat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَبَسَ",
        "answer": "He frowned",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 950,
        "tlit": "ʿabasa",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " عَبَسَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَسَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to frown",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabasa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَعْمَىٰ",
        "answer": "the blind man",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1025,
        "tlit": "l-aʿmā",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ جَاءَهُ الْأَعْمَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْمَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "so they became blind",
        "waznTlit": "aʿmā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعِنَبًا",
        "answer": "And grapes",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1026,
        "tlit": "waʿinaban",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَعِنَبًا وَقَضْبًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ن ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ن ب",
        "waznEnglish": "and grapevines",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn nūn bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَبَرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) dust",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1048,
        "tlit": "ghabaratun",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ عَلَيْهَا غَبَرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "غ ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَبَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(will be) dust",
        "waznTlit": "ghabarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "غُلْبًا",
        "answer": "(of) thick foliage",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1073,
        "tlit": "ghul'ban",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَدَائِقَ غُلْبًا",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غُلْب",
        "waznEnglish": "overcame",
        "waznTlit": "ghul'b",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُغْنِيهِ",
        "answer": "occupying him",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "yugh'nīhi",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لِكُلِّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ شَأْنٌ يُغْنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "considers himself free from need",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "is'taghnā",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمَّا مَنِ اسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be self",
        "waznTlit": "is'taghnā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَجَرَةُ",
        "answer": "the wicked ones",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1108,
        "tlit": "l-fajaratu",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ هُمُ الْكَفَرَةُ الْفَجَرَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ف ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فُجَّار",
        "waznEnglish": "you cause to gush forth",
        "waznTlit": "fujjār",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَفِرُّ",
        "answer": "will flee",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1118,
        "tlit": "yafirru",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَفِرُّ الْمَرْءُ مِنْ أَخِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرَّتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to flee",
        "waznTlit": "farrat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَاكِهَةً",
        "answer": "And fruits",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "wafākihatan",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَاكِهَةً وَأَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰكِهَة",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fākihat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَقْبَرَهُ",
        "answer": "and provides a grave for him",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1171,
        "tlit": "fa-aqbarahu",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَمَاتَهُ فَأَقْبَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to provide a grave",
        "waznTlit": "aqbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَتَرَةٌ",
        "answer": "darkness",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1175,
        "tlit": "qataratun",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْهَقُهَا قَتَرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ت ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَتَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and are not stingy",
        "waznTlit": "qatarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُتِلَ",
        "answer": "Is destroyed",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 1176,
        "tlit": "qutila",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قُتِلَ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا أَكْفَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ت ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَتَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to kill",
        "waznTlit": "qatala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَدَّرَهُ",
        "answer": "then He proportioned him",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "faqaddarahu",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ نُطْفَةٍ خَلَقَهُ فَقَدَّرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَضْبًا",
        "answer": "and green fodder",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1210,
        "tlit": "waqaḍban",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَعِنَبًا وَقَضْبًا",
        "rootWord": "ق ض ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ض ب",
        "waznEnglish": "and green fodder",
        "waznTlit": "qāf ḍād bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقْضِ",
        "answer": "he has accomplished",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 1212,
        "tlit": "yaqḍi",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَمَّا يَقْضِ مَا أَمَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ض ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَضَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to decree, to decide, to judge",
        "waznTlit": "qaḍā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِرَامٍ",
        "answer": "Noble",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "kirāmin",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كِرَامٍ بَرَرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُكَرَّمَةٍ",
        "answer": "honored",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "mukarramatin",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي صُحُفٍ مُكَرَّمَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَرَّمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "mukarramat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَكْفَرَهُ",
        "answer": "ungrateful is he",
        "pcklId": "303",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "akfarahu",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قُتِلَ الْإِنْسَانُ مَا أَكْفَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكْفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be ngrateful, to deny",
        "waznTlit": "akfara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَفَرَةُ",
        "answer": "(are) the disbelievers",
        "pcklId": "328",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "l-kafaratu",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ هُمُ الْكَفَرَةُ الْفَجَرَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَافِر",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfir",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِكُلِّ",
        "answer": "For every",
        "pcklId": "353",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "likulli",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِكُلِّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ شَأْنٌ يُغْنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَلَهَّىٰ",
        "answer": "(are) distracted",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1355,
        "tlit": "talahhā",
        "frequency": "16",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْتَ عَنْهُ تَلَهَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ل ه و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَلَهَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to distract, to divert",
        "waznTlit": "talahhā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَتَاعًا",
        "answer": "(As) a provision",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "matāʿan",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " مَتَاعًا لَكُمْ وَلِأَنْعَامِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَتَٰع",
        "waznEnglish": "[then] I will grant him enjoyment",
        "waznTlit": "matāʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "امْرِئٍ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1381,
        "tlit": "im'ri-in",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِكُلِّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ شَأْنٌ يُغْنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "م ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱمْرِئ",
        "waznEnglish": "an evil man",
        "waznTlit": "im'ri",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَرْءُ",
        "answer": "a man",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1381,
        "tlit": "l-maru",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَفِرُّ الْمَرْءُ مِنْ أَخِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "م ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرْء",
        "waznEnglish": "an evil man",
        "waznTlit": "mar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمَاتَهُ",
        "answer": "He causes him to die",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "amātahu",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَمَاتَهُ فَأَقْبَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause death",
        "waznTlit": "amāta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَاءَ",
        "answer": "the water",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "l-māa",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّا صَبَبْنَا الْمَاءَ صَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَنْبَتْنَا",
        "answer": "Then We caused to grow",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1435,
        "tlit": "fa-anbatnā",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا حَبًّا",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنۢبَتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make grow",
        "waznTlit": "anbata",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَخْلًا",
        "answer": "and date-palms",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1452,
        "tlit": "wanakhlan",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَزَيْتُونًا وَنَخْلًا",
        "rootWord": "ن خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَخْل",
        "waznEnglish": "the date-palm",
        "waznTlit": "nakhl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْشَرَهُ",
        "answer": "He will resurrect him",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1471,
        "tlit": "ansharahu",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِذَا شَاءَ أَنْشَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنشَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to raise, to revive, to resurrect",
        "waznTlit": "anshara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُطْفَةٍ",
        "answer": "a semen-drop",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1485,
        "tlit": "nuṭ'fatin",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ نُطْفَةٍ خَلَقَهُ فَقَدَّرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ط ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ط ف",
        "waznEnglish": "a minute quantity of semen",
        "waznTlit": "nūn ṭā fā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَلْيَنْظُرِ",
        "answer": "Then let look",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "falyanẓuri",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلْيَنْظُرِ الْإِنْسَانُ إِلَىٰ طَعَامِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلِأَنْعَامِكُمْ",
        "answer": "and for your cattle",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "wali-anʿāmikum",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مَتَاعًا لَكُمْ وَلِأَنْعَامِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّعَم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿam",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَنْفَعَهُ",
        "answer": "so would benefit him",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1502,
        "tlit": "fatanfaʿahu",
        "frequency": "50",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوْ يَذَّكَّرُ فَتَنْفَعَهُ الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to profit, to benifit",
        "waznTlit": "nafaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وُجُوهٌ",
        "answer": "Faces",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 1592,
        "tlit": "wujūhun",
        "frequency": "78",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ مُسْفِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجْه",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] have turned",
        "waznTlit": "wajh",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَوُجُوهٌ",
        "answer": "And faces",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1592,
        "tlit": "wawujūhun",
        "frequency": "78",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ عَلَيْهَا غَبَرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجْه",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] have turned",
        "waznTlit": "wajh",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and turned away",
        "pcklId": "105",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "watawallā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَبَسَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِأَيْدِي",
        "answer": "In (the) hands",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 1657,
        "tlit": "bi-aydī",
        "frequency": "120",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَيْدِي سَفَرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي د ي",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) them",
        "waznTlit": "yā dāl yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّرَهُ",
        "answer": "He made easy for him",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yassarahu",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ السَّبِيلَ يَسَّرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "399",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "80",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَفِرُّ الْمَرْءُ مِنْ أَخِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    }
]